

Bruno Fernandes Assumpção

Date of birth: 1990 Nationality: Portuguese Phone number: (+351) 924313889 (Mobile)

Email address: <u>brunofassumpcao@outlook.com</u> | **Website:**

https://bruno-f-assumpcao.github.io/Bruno/#about | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bruno-assumpção-b8948a195/ Address: Lisbon, Portugal (Home)

ABOUT ME

I am an experienced Business Intelligence & Data Analyst focused on data driven business models, I am also experienced in Project and Operations Management. My goal is to elevate the business with descriptive insights based on factual data and provide answers to the business reality (what, when, where, why and how) to aid the Stakeholders on decision making.

WORK EXPERIENCE

08/2024 – CURRENT Lisbon, Portugal **BUSINESS ANALYST** EVA GLOBAL

- In charge of Data transformation, modeling and presentation in PowerBi and Quicksight Dashboards, personalized reports, triggered data alerts and Business review presentations.
- Close communication with Stakeholders in order do understand the business questions and requirements for continuous improvement with data driven business model.
- Providing descriptive statistical analysis on trends and correlations between KPIs in order to provide deeper understanding of the business reality and areas of improvement.

09/2022 - 08/2024 Lisbon, Portugal

MIS BUSINESS ANALYST COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS - GOOGLE CSA

MIS BA - In charge of ETL, data integrity assurance and data modeling to provide visual insights on the project's metrics and SLAs for the Google CSA project (Customer Success Acceleration) in the field of Digital Marketing (Search, Display, Video, Shopping). I am currently in charge of providing historic, real time and forecast analytical dashboards and client facing reportings from Operational and Business Fronts (B2B) for EMEA, AMER and APAC.

05/2022 - 09/2022

BUSINESS DATA ANALYST TELEPERFORMANCE PORTUGAL

In charge of ETL (extract, transform and load), data and query validation, and creation of visual reportings in PowerBi to provide KPI insights and forecast to the Operations. During the time I was part of a team working with Data engineers to create the global Data modeling and relational schemas following the company's standards.

03/08/2020 - 04/2022

OPERATIONS MANAGER TELEPERFORMANCE PORTUGAL

Supervision and management of the German and Engish markets.

Responsible for leading and developing a team of representatives in order to achieve excellency in Quality and Service Level. Providing accurate KPI reporting and dashboards to the Operations, as well as being part of the Data Analytics and Work Force Management meetings.

04/08/2019 - 02/08/2020

OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT AUDITOR TELEPERFORMANCE PORTUGAL

- Auditor of Operational Process and Standards Assurance for Operations Management for COPC compliance (First Line Managers, Assistant Call Center Managers and Call Center Managers).

As an Operations Management Auditor, my main goal was to ensure the process and quality compliance in order to exponentially increase the return on investment and positive Gross Margin.

01/06/2017 - 03/08/2019

OPERATIONS SUPERVISOR TELEPERFORMANCE PORTUGAL

- Supervision and management for the Portuguese and Persian/Farsi markets for online Gaming Support. Responsible for leading and developing a team of representatives in order to achieve excellency in Quality and service level.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

02/2024 - CURRENT Porto, Portugal

POST GRADUATION IN BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE & ANALYTICS Porto Business School - University of Porto

Website https://www.pbs.up.pt/

THE FUNDAMENTALS OF DIGITAL MARKETING - 9RG AU8 6X3 Google

Website https://learndigital.withgoogle.com/digitalgarage/validate-certificate-code

SQL DATA ANALYST - MICROSOFT SQL Bluelime Learning Solutions - Udemy

POWERBI QUERY CERTIFICATE Udemy

POWERBI INTRODUCTION - TRANSFORMING DATA SOURCES; CREATING AND PUBLISHING REPORTS Udemy

GOOGLE SHEETS CERTIFICATE - THE COMPLETE GOOGLE SHEETS COURSE Udemy

INTERNAL AUDITOR CERTIFICATION - OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT AUDITOR Teleperformance Portugal

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **PORTUGUESE**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
GERMAN	A2	A2	A2	A2	A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

JOB-RELATED SKILLS

Developing Job-related skills

Currently, I am developing skills and knowledge in data mining for predictive and prescriptive statistical models in business intelligence and data science.

I am also learning about LLMs (Large Language Models) to implement and elevate AI and GEN AI usage.

Developed Job-related skills

ETL, Data Modeling, Query Modeling and creation of descriptive dashboards and visual insights in Spreadsheets (Excel, GoogleSheets), PowerBi, Tableau, LookerStudio, Quicksight and PLX.

Deep understanding and implementation capability of the Six Sigma methodology and Lean Approach, as well as the DMAIC tool for problem solving processes.

Deep understanding and capability for team and individual management, as well as coaching tools and methodologies of continuous improvement (root cause and behavior analysis, points of improvement, action plans and SMART goals).